Guide to the Health Systems Management Group, School of Organization and Management, Yale University, Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Records, 1974-1987; Accession 1989-A-105
  - Miscellaneous Reports and Papers
    - Development, Testing and Evaluation of a Prospective Case Payment Reimbursement System: Progress Report Oct 1978 (Box 19, Folder 402)
    - Development, Testing and Evaluation of a Prospective Case Payment Reimbursement System: Final Report (Box 19, Folder 403)
    - Ambulatory Patient Related Groups (Box 19, Folder 404)
    - Implementation of a Management by a Diagnosis System (Box 19, Folder 405)
    - H-ICDA Conversion Tables (Box 19, Folder 406)
    - Group Analysis Capability (Box 19, Folder 407)
    - Grouping Algorithm (Box 19, Folder 408)
    - Cost Containment and Hopital Reimbursement under Medicare and Medicaid (Box 19, Folder 409)
    - CML7: Installation and Extensions, Instructions with Examples (Box 19, Folder 410)
    - Interactive Production Scheduling System (Box 19, Folder 411)
    - Interactive Multivariable Profile Analysis (Box 19, Folder 412)
    - Case Mix and Resource Use (Box 20, Folder 413)
    - Cost Benefit Analysis of Continued Stay Certification (Box 20, Folder 414)
    - CML System Programs (Box 20, Folder 415)
    - Case Mix Difference: J. Lion (Box 20, Folder 416)
    - Decision Models for Inventory Management (Box 20, Folder 417)
    - Installation of CM7 and its Extensions Under OS (Box 20, Folder 418)
    - Installation of CM7 and its Extensions under CMS Instructions with Examples (Box 20, Folder 419)
    - Utilization Objectives for the CT II PSRO (Box 20, Folder 420)
    - University Teaching Hospitals and Cost Control ill. 757 (Box 20, Folder 421)
    - Prospective Reimbursement Based on DRG's (Box 20, Folder 422)
    - Proposed Rate Setting Regulation for Reimbursement of LTC Facilities (Box 20, Folder 423)
    - Problems, Prospects and an Alternative Approach in Simulation Modeling (Box 20, Folder 424)
    - Planning Model for the Delivery of Health Services (Box 20, Folder 425)
    - A Model for Catastrophic Health Insurance Plan (Box 20, Folder 426)
    - A Micro-Computer Based Medical Information System (Box 20, Folder 428)
    - University and Non-University Hospitals (Box 20, Folder 429)
    - A Language to Aid in Manpower Planning (Box 20, Folder 430)
    - LMC Tutorial (Box 20, Folder 431)
    - Measurement Issues in the Development of a Hospital Case Mix Index for Medicare (Box 20, Folder 432)
    - A Management Control Model for Health Care Organizations (Box 20, Folder 433)
    - Medicare - Federal Register (Box 20, Folder 434)
    - Medicine and Profits: Unhealthy Mixture ? (Box 20, Folder 435)
    - Application of Diagnostic Specific Cost Profiles to Cost and Reimbursement Control in Hospitals (Box 20, Folder 436)
    - Application of Cost and Quality Control Technology in Hospitals (Box 20, Folder 437)
    - The Application of Case-Mix Cost Accounting to Hospital Budgeting and Prospective Reimbursement (Box 20, Folder 438)
    - Application of a Case-Mix Methodology in Hospitals (Box 20, Folder 439)
    - Initial Gouping Strategy: New 78 Initial Groups (Box 20, Folder 440)
    - 83 Initial Groups: Diagnostic Categories (Box 20, Folder 441)
    - Information Systems Language (Box 20, Folder 442)
    - Hospism (Box 20, Folder 443)
    - Fetter, VHS TranscripL Better Health episode 201 St. Raphael's (Box 20, Folder 444)
    - Economics of Occupancy wftTI Varying Mixes (Box 20, Folder 445)
    - Economics of the Maternity Service (Box 20, Folder 446)
    - Development of a Generalized Hospital Planning System (Box 20, Folder 447)
  - SOM Adminstrative Files
    - SOM Liason Meetins Sep 1986 - Apr 1987 (Box 20, Folder 448)
    - SOM Faculty Meetings Dec 1986 - Apr 1987 (Box 20, Folder 449)
    - Board Meeting (BPO Jun 8) (Box 20, Folder 450)
    - Board Meetings (BPO Jan 1986 - Jun 1987) (Box 20, Folder 451)
    - OR Faculty (Box 20, Folder 452)
    - 1979-80 684B-38-00001 (Box 20, Folder 453)
    - BQA Final Statement (Box 20, Folder 454)
    - French Ministry 55840 (Box 20, Folder 455)
    - Executive Education Alumni Session (Box 20, Folder 456)
    - Gift Statements (Box 20, Folder 457)
    - Travel Expense Forms Jul- 1978 - Juri 1979 (Box 21, Folder 458)
    - Expenses Jul 1978 - Jun 1979 (Box 21, Folder 459)
  - SOM Class Notes and Materials
    - PPM 114b: Computing and Management (I) (Box 21, Folder 460)
    - PPM 114b: Computing and Management (II) (Box 21, Folder 461)
    - Production II 1983-84 (I) (Box 21, Folder 462)
    - Production II 1983-84 (II) (Box 21, Folder 463)
  - Video Tapes [PDP]
    - PDP/II Lecture #1 (Box 22)
    - PDP-I1-ASM 111 (Box 22)
    - PDP-I1-ASM #2 (Box 22)
    - PDP-I1-ASM 113 (Box 22)
    - PDP-I1-ASM 116 (Box 22)
    - PDP-I1-ASM 117 (Box 22)
    - PDP 11 #8 (Box 22)
    - PDP 11 #9 (Box 22)
    - PDP 11 #10 (Box 22)
    - PDP 11 #11 (Box 22)
    - PDP #11 (Box 22)
  - Video Tape [PM]
    - PM/II 6/10/81 #1 (Box 22)
    - PM/II 6/10/81 #2 (Box 22)
    - PM/II 6/10/81 #3 (Box 22)
    - PM/II 6/10/81 #4 (Box 22)
    - PM/II 6/10/81 #5 (Box 22)
    - PM/II 6/10/81 #6 (Box 22)
    - PM/II 6/10/81 #7 (Box 22)
  - Video Tapes [AUTOGRP]
    General note
    see folder #375
    - AUTOGRP 1 and 2 9/18/74 edited (Box 23)
    - AUTOGRP tape 3 (Box 23)
    - AUTOGRP Lecture 3 unedited Lindgren (Box 23)
    - AUTOGRP 1st ISPS Brauer 9/20/74 (Box 23)
    - 3rd AUTOGRP Class Brauer (Box 23)
    - Brauer (AUTOGRP Class?) (Box 23)
    - AUTOGRP 5 (Box 23)
  - Video Tape [PSRO]
    - PSRO Lecture #2 (Box 23)
    - PSRO Lecture #3 (Box 23)
    - PSRO Lecture #6 (Box 23)
    - PSRO Lecture #7 (Box 23)
  - Video Tapes [Miscellaneous]
    - Reel #2 (Box 23)
    - Reel #4 Essex Multnomah (Box 23)
    - NO TITLE (Box 23)
    - CML EXPRN (edited) (Box 23)
    - C-Mass #1 12/7/78 (Box 23)
  - Audio Tapes [Alumni]
    - Alumni II Friday 9:00 - 10:15 (Box 23)
    - Alumni II Saturday 4/17/82 9:00 - 12:00 (Box 23)
    - Alumni Session tape 1, EPHM, Friday 10/31/80 (Box 23)
    - Alumni Session tape 2, EPHM, Friday 10/31/80 (Box 23)
    - Alumni Session tape 3, EPHM, Saturday 11/1/80 (Box 23)
  - Audio Tapes [EPHM 4]
    - EPHM 4 Tuesday 6/16/81 (Box 24)
    - EPHM 4 Wednesday 6/17/81 (Box 24)
    - EPHM 4 Thursday 6/18/81 (Box 24)
    - EPHM 4 Friday 6/19/81 (Box 24)
  - Audio Tapes [EPHM 5]
    - EPHM 5 Monday 6/14/82 (Box 24)
    - EPHM 5 Monday P.M. RBF Lecture 6/14/82 (Box 24)
    - EPHM 5 Monday P.M. RBF Lecture (cont'd)/ Tuesday 6/15/82 (Box 24)
    - EPHM 5 Tuesday P.M. 6/15/82 (Box 24)
    - EPHM 5 Wednesday 6/16/82 (Box 24)
    - EPHM 5 Thursday 6/17/82 (Box 24)
    - EPHM 5 Thursday 6/17/82 (NJ Panel) (Box 24)
  - Audio Tapes [EP/HMO I]
    - EP/HMO I Monday 1/4/82 9:00 - 3:00 JRK (Box 24)
    - EP/HMO I Monday 1/4/82 2:00 - 5:15 RBF (Box 24)
    - EP/HMO I Tuesday 1/5/82 9:00 - 2:30 (Box 24)
    - EP/HMO I Tuesday 4:00 - 5:15 JDT / Wednesday 9:00 - 10:30 JRK (Box 24)
    - EP/HMO I Wednesday 1/6/82 11:00 - 1:45 (Box 24)
    - EP/HMO I Thursday 1/7/82 9:00 - 3:30 (Box 24)
    - EP/HMO I Thursday 1/7/82 3:45 - 5:30 (Box 24)
  - Audio Tapes [Exec Ed - EPHM I]
    - Exec Ed I, II (Box 24)
    - Exec Ed ill, IV (Box 24)
    - Exec Ed V, VI (Box 24)
    - Exec Ed VII, VII (Box 24)
    - Exec Ed IX, X (Box 24)
    - Exec Ed XI, XII (Box 24)
    - Exec Ed XIII (Box 24)
  - Video Tapes [Exec Ed in Health Management]
    - Exec Ed in Health Management 7/13/79 #1 (Box 24)
    - Exec Ed in Health Management 7/13/79 #2 (Box 24)
    - Exec Ed in Health Management 7/13/79 #3 (Box 24)
    - Exec Ed in Health Management 7/13/79 #4 (Box 24)
  - Video Tapes [EP/HMO I]
    - EP/RMO I 111 (1) (Box 25)
    - EP/HMO I 2nd Class (1) (Box 25)
    - EP/RMO I (Box 25)
  - Video Tapes [Exec Ed II]
    - Exec Ed II 12/14/79 Friday Evaluation Session III (Box 25)
    - Exec Ed II 12/14/79 Friday Evaluation Session 112 (Box 25)
    - Exec Ed IT 12/14/79 Friday Evaluation Session 113 (Box 25)
    - Exec Ed II 12/14/79 Friday Evaluation Session 114 (Box 25)
  - Video Tapes [EPHM 3] - 3 tapes all with the same label
    - EPHM 3, 1980 June (Box 25)
    - EPHM 3, 1980 June (Box 25)
    - EPHM 3, 1980 June (Box 25)
  - Video Tapes [EPHM 4] - 3 tapes all with the same label
    - EPHM JY Friday 6/19/81 (Box 25)
    - EPHM JY Friday 6/19/81 (Box 25)
    - EPHM N Friday 6/19/81 (Box 25)
  - Tape Outlines
    - Tape Outlines (Box 25, Folder 464)
- Video and audio tapes, circa 1975-1982; Accession 1989-A-116
  The materials are open for research.
  - Class Discussion CT. Sean Case, 1980 January 29 (Box 1)
    H.P. and M Kimberly
  - Side I: H.M. Colloquian, 1980 February 6 (Box 1)
    - H.P. And M "Protocols", 1980 February 13 (Box 1)
  - Side II: H.P.and M "Protocols", 1980 February 13 (Box 1)
  - ER Protocol I, 1980 March 5 (Box 1)
  - HM Colloquian, Dennis May, 1980 April 16 (Box 1)
  - HM Colloquian, Davis Rosenbloom, 1980 April 2 (Box 1)
  - DRG's, undated (Box 1)
  - DRG's #8, 18-January (Box 1)
  - DRG's Private Management and Public Policy 1 and 2, undated (Box 1)
  - #1 Hospital Costs - New Haven, CT, undated (Box 1)
    Host: Hooyce Phillips
    Guests: Jack F. Croweak, Dennis May
  - Health Discussion, 1979 June 4 (Box 1)
  - Health Group 1 and 2, 1979 April 4 (Box 1)
  - SOM PPM 303 A Tape I 60 minutes, 28-November (Box 1)
    Health Policy and Management
    ARH Case Presentation
  - PDP-11 Assembler, undated (Box 1)
  - PM-II (SLP) Funny Girl, undated (Box 1)
  - Language Building in PM-11 (SP speed), undated (Box 1)
  - Series on PM-II PML RON MILLS
    - Lecture #1 LSI-II Hardware, 1982 May 19 (Box 1)
    - Lecture #2 Operating Systems, 1982 May 24 (Box 1)
    - Lecture #3 Assembly Language, 1982 June 25 (Box 1)
  - CML # 1 and 2, 1975 August 26 (Box 2)
  - CML # 3 and 4, 1975 August 27 (Box 2)
  - CML Lectues 2,5,6,7,8,10,11,12,13, 1976 June 14-17 (Box 2)
  - CML Parameter Conventions, undated (Box 2)
  - Reel 3 SRO Data Continued, 1978 December 7-8 (Box 2)
  - End AM Session, 1978 December 7 (Box 2)
  - Marjorie Winkler room's class, undated (Box 2)
  - Unidentified tape of a lecture (Box 2)